<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo-Site on S-cubed</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/hugo-site/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo-Site on S-cubed</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/hugo-site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A first post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/spoonful-series/01-spoonful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/spoonful-series/01-spoonful/</guid>
      <description> Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.&#xA;Here I am: content/blog\spoonful-series\01-spoonful.md To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}&#xA;My content section is: blog My layout is: single-series does this work? or this? Let&amp;rsquo;s start.&#xA;beginning middle end </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A second post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/spoonful-series/02-spoonful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/spoonful-series/02-spoonful/</guid>
      <description> Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.&#xA;Here I am: content/blog\spoonful-series\02-spoonful\index.md To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}&#xA;My content section is: blog My layout is: single-series Images in this page bundle: /blog/spoonful-series/02-spoonful/sidebar-inverse.jpg part 2! does this work? now for some very cool things more get ready! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A third post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/spoonful-series/03-spoonful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/spoonful-series/03-spoonful/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.&#xA;Here I am: content/blog\spoonful-series\03-spoonful\index.markdown Here is my R Markdown source file: blog\spoonful-series\03-spoonful\index.Rmarkdown You&#39;ll want to edit this file, then re-knit to see the changes take effect in your site preview.&#xA;To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}&#xA;My content section is: blog My layout is: single-series Images in this page bundle: /blog/spoonful-series/03-spoonful/featured-photo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tachyons for Style</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/giraffes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/giraffes/</guid>
      <description>Tachyons is a design system that allows you to design gorgeous interfaces in the browser with little effort. Because Speed Building this static site generator theme was the first time I used an Atomic (or Functional) CSS system like Tachyons. It&amp;rsquo;s a design system that provides very small (which means fast) CSS modules that you can use in your HTML. So, rather than writing every line of CSS, you apply the style you need as you write your HTML with easy to understand shorthand class names.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSS Grid Scaffold</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/css-grid-scaffold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/css-grid-scaffold/</guid>
      <description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.” — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1&#xA;Overview Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palmer Penguins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/intro_stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/intro_stats/</guid>
      <description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.” — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1&#xA;Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips. Most times, while fighting with floats and widths of content and sidebars or just basically trying to get something beside something else without using a stupid TABLE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Contact Form</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/built-in-contact-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/built-in-contact-form/</guid>
      <description>Formspree makes it easy to receive submissions from HTML forms on your static website. Functional Form This theme has a form-to-email feature built in, thanks to the simple Formspree integration. All you need to activate the form is a valid recipient email address saved in the front matter of the form (/content/forms/contact.md). Of course, the example shown below (your@email.here) must not be used. Please use your actual email address.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian data analysis with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/bayesian_stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/bayesian_stats/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Intermediate&#xA;Next live dates: TBC (Contact us to request training details).&#xA;Course description Throughout our lives, in everything we do, we will have some prior belief about what the result of an action will be, often based on previous experiences. For example, when I take the train to London, I expect to arrive around 20 minutes later than scheduled as UK trains are notoriously unreliable! Bayesian inference allows us to take account of our prior beliefs and incorporate them into our analysis using Bayes’ theorem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data visualisation with ggplot2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/data_viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/data_viz/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Next live dates: TBC ( Contact us to request training details)&#xA;Course description Data visualisation is one of the most important steps in any analysis journey. Visualisations allow us to explore our data, identify errors and outliers, generate hypotheses about possible relationships between variables, and communicate results clearly and efficiently. ggplot2 is a powerful R package that was designed to create publication-quality graphics in seconds. The joy of ggplot2 is its flexibility: graphs are built in layers which can be easily customised, ensuring novel plots to fit almost any situation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inferential statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/inferential_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/inferential_statistics/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Self-paced course available FREE here&#xA;Course description The aim of statistical analysis is often to make inferences about a target population of interest based on a random sample from it. Inferences such as these require inferential statistics.&#xA;This micro-course will introduce two of the most common inferential statistics: p-values and confidence intervals. Although these statistics are widely used across many disciplines, their interpretation can be tricky, which can lead to them being misrepresented.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Generalised Additive Models with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/generalised_additive_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/generalised_additive_models/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Intermediate&#xA;Next live dates: TBC ( Contact us to request training details)&#xA;Course description Generalised additive models (GAMs) take regression to the next level, allowing a more flexible exploration of our data. Unlike generalised linear models, GAMs do not assume a linear relationship between the outcome and covariate(s). Using smoothing functions, we can explore nonlinear trends, such as the impact of temperature on barbecue food sales, or the relationship between income and happiness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R with Tidyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/intro_r_tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/intro_r_tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Next live dates: 15 - 16th June, 2024.&#xA;Course description R is a popular open-source programming language used by data scientists, statisticians, social &amp;amp; health researchers, and many more across a wide range of disciplines. R is particularly appealing to researchers as it is free to access, designed to encourage collaborative and reproducible data analysis, and is constantly evolving to include the latest research developments.&#xA;This two-day workshop is designed to equip PhD students, academics, and professional researchers across various disciplines with the essential skills to leverage the power of R and Tidyverse for their academic research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to regression with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/regression_with_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/regression_with_r/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Next live dates: TBC Contact us to request training details.&#xA;Course description Regression analysis is one of the most widely used and powerful quantitative analysis methods used across almost every sector. Regression models were designed to investigate the relationship between an outcome of interest and a set of explanatory variables. These methods can then be used to make inferences about underlying relationships between variables, while accounting for confounding factors, and can be used to make predictions based on existing data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to statistical thinking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/statistical_thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/statistical_thinking/</guid>
      <description>Course level: foundation&#xA;Next live course dates: TBC Click here to request training details.&#xA;Course description Many people assume that statistics require complex analysis methods but often, the simplest approaches can be the most effective. This course focuses on the concept of statistically thinking, describing data and complex systems in relatively simple terms whilst acknowledging underlying uncertainty.&#xA;Statistical thinking is a necessary skill, not just in work but in our personal lives too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial data analysis with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/spatial_data_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/spatial_data_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Intermediate&#xA;Next live dates: TBC Contact us to request training details&#xA;Course description Spatial data analysis allows us to go beyond traditional investigation of data, and uncover relationships and patterns based on where things are. This adds an extra layer of understanding of our data which can aid us when making inferences and predictions.&#xA;Spatial data analysis has a wide range of applications across many different sectors. For example, improving access to healthcare, increasing efficiency in transport networks, identifying areas of expansion in retail and hospitality, and developing approaches to environmental preservation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
