<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on S-cubed</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/categories/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on S-cubed</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/categories/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian data analysis with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/bayesian_stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/bayesian_stats/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Intermediate&#xA;Next live dates: TBC (Contact us to request training details).&#xA;Course description Throughout our lives, in everything we do, we will have some prior belief about what the result of an action will be, often based on previous experiences. For example, when I take the train to London, I expect to arrive around 20 minutes later than scheduled as UK trains are notoriously unreliable! Bayesian inference allows us to take account of our prior beliefs and incorporate them into our analysis using Bayes’ theorem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inferential statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/inferential_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/inferential_statistics/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Self-paced course available FREE here&#xA;Course description The aim of statistical analysis is often to make inferences about a target population of interest based on a random sample from it. Inferences such as these require inferential statistics.&#xA;This micro-course will introduce two of the most common inferential statistics: p-values and confidence intervals. Although these statistics are widely used across many disciplines, their interpretation can be tricky, which can lead to them being misrepresented.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inferential statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/inferential_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/inferential_statistics/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Self-paced course available FREE here&#xA;Course description The aim of statistical analysis is often to make inferences about a target population of interest based on a random sample from it. Inferences such as these require inferential statistics.&#xA;This micro-course will introduce two of the most common inferential statistics: p-values and confidence intervals. Although these statistics are widely used across many disciplines, their interpretation can be tricky, which can lead to them being misrepresented.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to statistical thinking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/courses/statistical_thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/courses/statistical_thinking/</guid>
      <description>Course level: foundation&#xA;Next live course dates: TBC Click here to request training details.&#xA;Course description Many people assume that statistics require complex analysis methods but often, the simplest approaches can be the most effective. This course focuses on the concept of statistically thinking, describing data and complex systems in relatively simple terms whilst acknowledging underlying uncertainty.&#xA;Statistical thinking is a necessary skill, not just in work but in our personal lives too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/intro_stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/intro_stats/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Self-paced online course coming soon!&#xA;Course description Statistics is the science of data. This includes the collection and storage of data, the visualisation and analysis of samples of data, the interpretation of results, and the communication of these to a wider audience. In this course, participants will be introduced to the fundamental concepts of statistical analysis and the steps required to carry out valid, robust inferences on data.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
