<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on S-cubed</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on S-cubed</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data visualisation with ggplot2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/data_viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/data_viz/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Next live dates: TBC ( Contact us to request training details)&#xA;Course description Data visualisation is one of the most important steps in any analysis journey. Visualisations allow us to explore our data, identify errors and outliers, generate hypotheses about possible relationships between variables, and communicate results clearly and efficiently. ggplot2 is a powerful R package that was designed to create publication-quality graphics in seconds. The joy of ggplot2 is its flexibility: graphs are built in layers which can be easily customised, ensuring novel plots to fit almost any situation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inferential statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/inferential_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/inferential_statistics/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Self-paced course available FREE here&#xA;Course description The aim of statistical analysis is often to make inferences about a target population of interest based on a random sample from it. Inferences such as these require inferential statistics.&#xA;This micro-course will introduce two of the most common inferential statistics: p-values and confidence intervals. Although these statistics are widely used across many disciplines, their interpretation can be tricky, which can lead to them being misrepresented.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R with Tidyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/intro_r_tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/intro_r_tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Next live dates: 15 - 16th June, 2024.&#xA;Course description R is a popular open-source programming language used by data scientists, statisticians, social &amp;amp; health researchers, and many more across a wide range of disciplines. R is particularly appealing to researchers as it is free to access, designed to encourage collaborative and reproducible data analysis, and is constantly evolving to include the latest research developments.&#xA;This two-day workshop is designed to equip PhD students, academics, and professional researchers across various disciplines with the essential skills to leverage the power of R and Tidyverse for their academic research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R with Tidyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/statistical_thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/statistical_thinking/</guid>
      <description>Course level: foundation&#xA;Next live course dates: TBC Click here to request training details.&#xA;Course description Many people assume that statistics require complex analysis methods but often, the simplest approaches can be the most effective. This course focuses on the concept of statistically thinking, describing data and complex systems in relatively simple terms whilst acknowledging underlying uncertainty.&#xA;Statistical thinking is a necessary skill, not just in work but in our personal lives too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/intro_stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/intro_stats/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Self-paced online course coming soon!&#xA;Course description Statistics is the science of data. This includes the collection and storage of data, the visualisation and analysis of samples of data, the interpretation of results, and the communication of these to a wider audience. In this course, participants will be introduced to the fundamental concepts of statistical analysis and the steps required to carry out valid, robust inferences on data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regression with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/regression_with_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/regression_with_r/</guid>
      <description>Course level: Foundation&#xA;Next live dates: TBC Contact us to request training details.&#xA;Course description Regression analysis is one of the most widely used and powerful quantitative analysis methods used across almost every sector. Regression models were designed to investigate the relationship between an outcome of interest and a set of explanatory variables. These methods can then be used to make inferences about underlying relationships between variables, while accounting for confounding factors, and can be used to make predictions based on existing data.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
